Nicholas R. Johnson

Pittsburgh, PA - njohnson@nicholasrjohnson.com

www.nicholasrjohnson.com

I am a highly dedicated and experienced Full Stack Software Engineer and consultant with 13 years of increasing responsibility in warehouse voice solutions, defense readiness applications, moving logistics and customer sales software support. I have been in many development roles with a wide variety of development tools including C#.NET, Java, HTML, CSS, javascript, and SQLServer. I am seeking and aspire to assist with customer satisfaction by creating high quality products using the SDLC.

WORK EXPERIENCE

- Full Stack Developer Champion International Moving Canonsburg, PA October 2020-August 2024
 - -Converted Company Web Application from ASP.NET MVC to ASP.NET Core 8 MVC
 - -Programmed company Webapp with Knockout JS 2.0 javascript Framework and JQuery
 - -Developed tasks for proprietary, automated Mail System
 - -Implemented Automated Excel Spreadsheet Report System
 - -Supported and developed for In-House .NET Logistics Software using DevExpress and WPF with SQLServer
 - -Assisted in upgrading from EF6 to EFCore for DAL in our applications
 - -Engineered a custom version of MS Identity for our Vendors to log into the Pricing Application
 - Utilized External Logins on our Rating Web Application, making MS365 the main login for our users
 - Produced client that captures CDR records from 3CX servers to process them for our purposes
 - -Worked with texting system that automated SMS Messages to Customers using Venmo
 - -Received Leadership Mentoring from Atlas World Group
 - -Mentored two junior developers
 - -Lead Team of Developers, Tester, and Networking and Help Desk Specialist
- Self Employed Indiana, PA

August 2020-October 2020

- -Worked on United Ones, a ride share system for families of prisoners to visit their loved ones
- Worked on personal web application to brush up on old skills and advance to newer technologies
- -Started writing a game called Vesuvius that uses Box2D where a person throws little men into a volcano
- Software Services Engineer Lucas Systems Wexford, PA

July 2018-August 2020

- -Supported customers with over one hundred custom solutions using multiple platforms in the mobile execution solution domain
- -Managed software end to end through the SDLC
- -Analyzed and programmed SOL Server stored procedures
- -Developed a voice solution to allow for multi container warehouse picking.
- -Learned how to operate in an Agile Environment
- -Maintained good relationships with customers
- -Brought creativity and value to the team

- Software Engineer/Web Developer Kencove Farm Fence Supply Blairsville, PA August 2017-November 2017
 - -Began development of fencing application using Angular 4 and ASP.NET Core
 - -Supported large scale ERP
 - -Wrote interfaces to shipment APIs with C# and ASP.NET Framework
 - -Completed a wide variety of Help Desk tasks
 - -Managed Trucking Rate Query API and upgraded previous solution to use REST instead of SOAP
- Software Engineer/SharePoint Engineer SAIC

March 2012-August 2017

- -Developed Java web application using Spring MVC and Hibernate ORM
- -Administered SharePoint 2010 and 2013
- -Augmented Salesforce to work as Prison Management Software
- -Developed acronym finder using VBA
- -Wrote SharePoint web part to help with document processes
- Intern IUP Research Institute Business Technology Group

May 2010-December 2010

- -Developed defense readiness software using C#, JavaScript, Visual Studio, and TFS
- -Fielded software to client by going on location and helping with training
- -Presented on various technologies
- Technical Assistant IUP Work Study

September 2007-May 2010

- -Set up Windows XP network in College of Business
- -Developed Crystal Report for metrics
- -Created application for controlling computer shutdowns
- -Fixed hardware and completed a variety of Helpdesk Tasks

CERTIFICATIONS

- Secret Security Clearance while at SAIC
- CompTIA Security+ while at SAIC
- Working on AZ-900 and AZ-245

EDUCATION

• Indiana University of Pennsylvania (IUP) - Indiana, PA

May 2007-December 2012

Major: Applied Computer Science

Minor: Information Assurance

Rochester Institute of Technology (RIT) - Rochester, NY

September 2000-December 2004

Major: Computer Science

Minor: Physics

ACADEMIC HONORS

- Graduated Magna Cum Laude
- PPG Database Management Award from IUP 2009

An award given to the student with the highest grade in the database class, COSC341

- Member of RIT Honors Program
- Member of Computer Science House at RIT

VOLUNTEER EXPERIECE

- Mentored for the Trade Institute of Pittsburgh
- Mentored for Allison Park Church
- Assisted in Hospice Care at Indiana Hospice

COMPUTING EXPERIENCE

- Experience with Both Agile and Waterfall SDLC Models
- Have Worked with Test Driven Development (TDD)
- Understanding of Prompt Programming and AI
- Basic Understanding of Cloud Concepts, CI/CD, and Docker/Kubernetes
- Development Programs

VIM	Eclipse	Visual Studio
Git	TFS	SVN
Atlassian SW	BitBucket	Team City
DevExpress	MySQL	SQLServer

Programming Languages

C# **VBA** Java javascript COBOL TSQL Apex **TypeScript** Python

Web Development

HTML CSS Spring MVC jQuery **VB.NET** SharePoint JSP and Servlets Salesforce ASP.NET Core

Silverlight Bootstrap

Frameworks

.NET Spring Hibernate Django

WPF MVC MVVM Entity Framework 6 and Core

OSes

MacOS Ubuntu

Windows Server **Ubuntu Server**

- Avid Computer Enthusiast Who Experiments with Raspberry Pis and has own Ubuntu VPS
- Working on Learning Angular with a Small Project Using Node.js and CircleCI

References Available on Request